UTU Photographs 5139 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UTU Photographs
1979-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
United Transportation Union (UTU)
5139 P
1.78 cubic feet
1.8 linear ft.
Photographs.
UTU photos from conventions, portraits, and miscellaneous snapshots
7581792
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 24, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The United Transportation Union (UTU) is headquartered in Cleveland, Ohio. It is a broad-based, transportation labor union representing about 125,000 active and retired railroad, bus, mass transit, and airline workers in the United States.
In 1968 four brotherhoods' became interested in joining together to make one transporatation union, the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, the Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen and the Switchmen's Union of North America. The new union was to be called the United Transportation Union and came into existence on January 1, 1969, after an overwhelming vote of the 4 unions on December 10, 1968, in Chicago.
The first president was Charles Luna, formerly president of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, and had 230,000 members. The International Association of Railway Employees joined in 1970. The Railroad Yardmasters of America joined the union in 1985.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5139 AV: UTU Audio-Visual Material 5139 MB: UTU Memorabilia 5139: UTU Records 6055: UTU Additional Collective Bargaining Agreements 6023: UTU Additional Records 5164: UTU Canada Records 5622: UTU New York State Legislative Board Selected Files 5711: UTU New York State Legislative Director Files 5589: UTU Vice-President's Office George W. Legg Subject Files 5501 AV: UTU. Young Leadership Conference Audio recordings 5196: UTU Ladies' Auxiliary Iowa Joint Board Minutes
Transport workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Wages -- Transport workers -- United States; United Transportation Union -- Photographs
7581792
- Air Traffic Controllers Strike (removed from 5139/box 58) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Group Photograph (removed from 5139/box 68) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Amtrak photographs, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  4 photos found in 5583/1, box 15, ff7 and moved to here.
- National Draeger, Inc. (removed from 5139/box 52) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Antwerp Engine No. 17, R W &; O RR (Box 2, Folder 1)
  1 Photograph
- Crew Members (Box 2, Folder 2)
  8 Photographs; includes: some members' names, engine names, and railroad stations.
- Dedication Site of BRTs defeat to SUNA (Box 2, Folder 3)
  2 Photographs
- Engine 1019 ICCRR (Illinois Central Railroad) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Installation Officers John and Jeanette Norling (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Manilla, PI, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  3 Photographs; includes: railroad devices used for transport.
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 7)
  4 Photographs; includes: baby photo of Pierce Richard Wolf; pictures Niles, Arsenueau, Fallon, Graves, Berg, Rein, Norling, Bliss, Mann, Hanrahan; gathering on Dec. 31, 1946 (names of participants on back of each photo).
- Various stages of raising M. U. (multiple unit) car No. 6704 on Sunday, October 18, 1906 near Atlantic City, NJ. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  4 Photographs
- Trains (Box 2, Folder 9)
  2 Photographs; Includes: 1889 picture of train 915 at Binghamton (NY?) engine house with engineer Harry Tibbits and fireman John Kistler; Engine 12, "Millie."
- Crew standing with wreckage of engine 2027, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  1 Photograph; November 2, 1906.
- Misc. Railroad Photos - "Camelback Engine" (Box 2, Folder 11)
  3 photographs
- UTU Officer Photos (Box 2, Folder 12)
  removed from 5139 - bx 2, ff5 -- 3 photographs
- UTU Officer Photos (Box 2, Folder 13)
  was removed from 5139, bx 2, ff5 -- 2 photographs
- Unification documents (Box 2, Folder 14)
  was removed from 5139, bx 1, ff3 and bx 7 -- 2 photographs
- Beam salutes a great American legend with the Casey Jones Decanter (Box 2, Folder 15)
  was removed from 5139, bx 7 -- 1 photograph
- Pre-Test & Post-Test photos of Train to Train Impact Test No. 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  48 photos
- Train to Train Impact Test No. 9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  1 photograph
- Pre-Test & Post-Test Photos of Train to Train Impact Test No. 9 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  45 photographs
- 3rd Convention - Miami Beach, Fla.: June 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  panoramic photo
- The United Transportation Union, Fifth Convention, Miami Beach, Florida - Oct. 1, 1987: Photo by Dore - Mark Davis (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 4th Convention, Miami Beach, Fla.: 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Forty Man Unification Committee, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  1 photograph. Hot Springs, Arkansas
- Union Pacific Locomotive no.809 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  1 photograph. Steam locomotive.
- Union Pacific Locomotive no.820 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  1 photograph. Steam locomotive
- Pennsylvania RR Polk Street Freight Station (Box 4, Folder 4)
  1 photograph. Chicago, Illinois. Includes Burlington (CB&Q) RR passenger train led by diesel-electric locomotive #9961A-C.
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 14)
  pulled from 5139/box 84
- Photo Postcard - 33rd Annual Convention: BRT (1968) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  pulled from 5139/box 79
- Unlabeled slides (Box 5, Folder 3)
  pulled from 5139/box 78
- Unlabeled Group Photograph (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Negatives and contact sheets (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Federal Railroad Admin. Toxicology Kit (Box 5, Folder 6)
  pulled from 5139/box 88
- Unlabeled Group Photo (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Constitution Committee (Negs) (1987) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Sept. 24, 1987 - Portrait Photos (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Sept. 24, 1987 - Portrait Photos (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Sept. 24, 1987 - Portrait Photos (Box 5, Folder 11)
- D.W. Collins - 3/1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  pulled from 5139/box 75
- United Transportation Union Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Misc. Photos (Box 5, Folder 26)
  pulled from 5139/box 80
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 15)
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 16)
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 17)
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 18)
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 19)
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 20)
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 21)
- UTU Fourth Convention (Box 5, Folder 22)
- 1987 Convention Photos (Box 5, Folder 23)
- 1987 Convention Photos (Box 5, Folder 24)
- 1987 Convention Photos (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Misc. Photos (Box 5, Folder 12)
- UTU News - Rock Island Files - March 1982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  pulled from 5139 - box 105/ff8
- Officer Portraits - 1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Officer Portraits - 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Officer Portraits - 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Lou Corsi Photos (1983) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Lou Corsi Photos (1983) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Lou Corsi Photos (1983) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- UTU - head shots (Box 6, Folder 8)
- UTU - head shots (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Misc. Photos (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Misc. Photos (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Misc. Photos (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Contact sheets (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Misc. Photos (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Misc. Photos (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 7)